standardbredcanada.ca 2008-04-10

# Privacy Policy

[](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/sales/)[  
](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/sales/)  
[](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/services/)[  
](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/services/)[](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/marketing/)[  
](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/marketing/)[](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/sales/forsale.html)[  
](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/hfsboard/)[](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/classified/)[  
](http://www.standardbredcanada.ca/classified/) [](https://trackit.standardbredcanada.ca/)  
|  |  |    
  
**Privacy Agreement**

When you apply for, or renew, your membership with Standardbred Canada, you agree that:

1\. We may collect, use and disclose personal information about you for purposes related to Standardbred Canada’s objects and mandate, and in particular:

a) To create a record of our membership and licensees.

b) To interchange information with the United States Trotting Association, provincial and state racing commissions (or their equivalent), horsemen’s associations, racetracks or racing officials.

c) To create, update and maintain breeding and ownership records for Standardbred Horses and, for that purpose, to interchange information with other standardbred breed associations throughout the world.

d) To operate the Membership Registry for Standardbred horses in Canada.

e) To create, update and maintain records and statistics regarding the racing of standardbred horses and, for that purpose, to interchange information with other horse racing organizations throughout the world.

f) To provide access to records and statistics regarding the breeding and racing of standardbred horses to persons or businesses with an interest in that information, with or without charging a fee.

g) To publish records of fines and suspensions as a matter of public interest.

h) To otherwise ensure your compliance with the by-laws and regulations of Standardbred Canada, including the rules of standardbred racing.

i) To meet our legal and regulatory requirements.

j) To investigate and assist in the resolution of insurance claims.

2\. Subject to obtaining your approval, we may use and disclose your personal information to persons who have an interest in providing products or services to you. If you give your consent, you may, on reasonable notice, revoke that consent thereafter.

3\. We may keep information about you in our records for as long as it is needed for the purposes mentioned above, even if you cease to be a member.  
4\. If any personal information changes or becomes inaccurate or out of date, you will tell us so that we can amend our records. You may in writing, request details of your personal information in our records.

5\. We have designated a [Privacy Officer](mailto:privacy%40standardbredcanada.ca "click here to contact") to deal with questions, complaints or concerns regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information.

 **Privacy Statement**  

In the course of discharging its mandate with respect to the breeding, ownership and racing of standardbred horses, Standardbred Canada collects, uses and discloses information personal to its members. This information is essential to the ongoing process of maintaining records that are vital to the industry. Because of the nature of the industry, the involvement of different regulatory bodies and the aspect of wagering, it is necessary that information regarding the breeding, ownership and racing of standardbred horses be accessible to the public and exchanged with other industry organizations that have a legitimate interest to its disclosure. Therefore, persons who participate in the industry are deemed to have consented to the collection and use of this information.

Standardbred Canada exchanges information with the United States Trotting Association and other breed organizations throughout the world. It also provides information in its database, including race results, industry statistics and records, to regulatory bodies (including provincial and state racing commissions or their equivalent) industry organizations, racetracks and racing officials.

Standardbred Canada also publishes notices of fines and suspensions as a matter of public interest.

Standardbred Canada is a non-profit organization and, in order to defray its costs of operation including the compiling and dissemination of these industry statistics and records, Standardbred Canada charges fees to various persons who access its database. In particular, fees are paid by certain businesses and individual users to access race entries, results and statistics relevant to wagering on Standardbred racing, as well as breeding and pedigree records which are relevant to the breeding of horses and the development of the standardbred breed.

It is, however, the policy of Standardbred Canada to preserve the confidentiality of personal information, except when disclosure of that information is reasonably necessary in the fulfillment of its mandate.

Standardbred Canada often receives inquiries from members, and other interested parties, including commercial interests who wish to provide goods and services, for contact information about its members, including telephone numbers or addresses. When responding to such inquiries is not directly related to Standardbred Canada’s mandate, members are entitled to control the release of information and specific consent is required.  

**Click here to return to the Standardbred Canada home page.**
